Hello programer, welcome back to today's new another tutorial topic. So today we are going to use MySQL date
Data type in MySQL is the fundamental type for working with the dates in the database
So simply explain for my school data
Data type used to store dates in the format we do allow us to perform the various operations and the comparison on dates
efficiently and here I'll create an explorer for how it works with the some examples. So first of all
You are simply a table of the date columns. Okay
So now just go in for here and type
This is a cleared for the table's name
Suppose like this is the events. Okay, so now here
the EV ENTES and it's a parenthesis and in this inside I can insert some columns. So first of all here
I can create a different idea. Okay, so define for the event
I did this the integer and this is the prime
key, okay, and this is where I will create a different name
so
EV ENT
Underscore and this is the name and
This is the worker and event name and here is the text size
100 and also here create
This is the most important for event underscore the date and it is completely used for the date. Okay
So now here simply defined and here first of all I can create it is completely defined for the
sample ID and now I have completely created this event table. Okay
So now just I can select and verify this and expect it for in this event
It's going to correct and now I can show for the confirmation message for the display
So now just select and run an execute and you can see the completely
So the message for this command is completely successful. Okay
So I hope you perfectly understand this so now just I can move on to the next for the second example. Okay
So now here I can just insert the data with the date column
So you must provide for the date in the correct format. Okay
So here I can insert perfectly and first of all here
I can just type this insert
into
the table name and suppose like
events, okay, and here I'll create the parenthesis inside. I can just type the event
ID
create for the
event underscore
name and also
where this event
underscore
date for the event. Okay, so now we can define perfectly and in this next line, I can insert for some
sample insert value for the data code. Okay, so first of all here. I can where the event ID is one. Okay
The next step here. I can create for event name. This is the
meeting. Okay, and also here insert for the event date is
24 and use the full month on the date for 30. Okay, and 30 and insert perfectly and
here simply create inserting the new event record events table for the event ID event name and
event data. Okay, so let's provide perfectly
format for here month and the date form. So here just select all and then execute. Now you can see here perfectly
in your own row is completely affected and in this my skill is completely returned a confirmation
message. Okay, so I hope you perfect understand and now here
I can create for the coding data based on the date. Okay, so you can see here
I'm looking for another new query and create in this example. So first of all, I can just type for
this is the select and then start for the multiplication sign from the table name. Suppose like this
events and use the y clause for suppose like this the event underscore date is greater than equal to
instead for the date of 2024 and use the full month and also the date title. Okay, so now
here this is completely different and here I can posting all this. Okay, and then execute. So now
you can see here the result of the output first is the event ID and second the event date.
Okay, so I hope you perfectly got your date value and in this down there are matching for record
and my school will return for the perfect results here. Okay, so here this is completely done for
the date data types in the my school and I hope you found this to your helpful. So stay tuned for
for more nice quality tips and tricks, so thank you for watching, okay?